Do it
[music]
jointly
how can you save the sick person from the reaction
when the company rejects the claim
how to raise voice against it how to get
your claim to answer all these questions
today my special
guest Shailesh Kumar co-founder of Insurance Samadhan
who also leads the insurance
thanks to you I used to have a
lot of conversations with you but today we
sat in porn video it was great
but we are going to talk to you that when the
company rejects you it is sad, it is
difficult you have to pay the bill by borrowing money in
such a situation the slippers are
Vijay so what is the first step for you consumers to take
because you people
yourself provide this solution to the people that
what should you do when the companies refuse you
this Nishan Samadhan helps in this
what do you suggest that the consumer should
do first of all thank you Priyanka ji now
people are going to forget the
first step you should wait for a
letter to come which says letter injection
and laptop radiation you will find written in it for
what reasons your cream is being
rejected you  You can take a vacation only
when you know it. First of all,
collect the information and
try to fill it in. If you are a lover of the
results and if you are a pilgrimage visitor, the
first complete documentation that you get is this detail after detail. It is
possible that the
disease for which you got the permit was done along with your
pre-existing diseases.
Now, this is the point on which a
dispute arises. Here the customer says
that he did not have any disease, but the
company this time claims that you had a pre-existing
disease. Now, there are proper medical records for that too. If you can
provide enough information about that, then
work can be done on it. And the
third addition is that some diseases are
not covered. There is a waiting period for these, there are
tuition fees.
You need to get information about them.
As far as pre-existing diseases are
concerned,
a lot of clarity is needed in that too. You can take
medical advice for that, you can
take advice from us and can vet you.
What is it and I do not do that, that
company, which I do not do at all. I
think  I should have got it, so where should I
go? If the company says that we have rejected it,
then where should I go? The policy holder should
first of all file a complaint with the
insurance company.
Subscribe above 329 loops in its question matrix. The problem
increases and to tell, express your emotions
because what happens is that when you, the customer,
complains, you feel
Radha Day Pack. So we tell everyone this,
write down the facts, what happened,
how it happened and their full details. When you submit the complaint, the
term will be heard, so
give him full details and take escalator,
different slip of because
when the nodal officer does not agree with you on this, then
you can approach the Ombudsman. If
your wish is below Rs 30 lakh,
it is above as per the amendment, then you
can go to the Consumer Forum and
put your complaint there. Okay,
if it is above Rs 30 lakh, then you will
go to the Consumer Forum.
Trishul spoon of less than that.  I will go but
before that you will follow the company's circulation matrix and lodge
your complaint there.
Now the question arises that you have
bought the policy and after one and a half years of buying the policy, you get diagnosed with a blood disease. So
what should I do then?
If the policy I bought was absolutely
fit and I did not have any disease. Now
after one and a half years of buying the policy, if I get diagnosed with a
disease, will it be
covered in my existing policy? Will I have to
call the company and inform them that I have got this
disease? How will that be reported?
See, this is a contract with the insurance.
Contract means the day
I took the policy,
how was my health on that day and
what was the situation? The entire contract is
based on this. For example,
I took the policy on 25th January. I have to tell you what was my health
status for January
2017. And for 1st
January, I would
like to ask you or any advisor.
Yes, on the day you take the policy, you must get
a health report and a medical checkup done on that day. It can be
from the insurance company or you can get your own medical checkup done. After getting a
cup done, put it in that water so that
this medical checkup is done.  It will help you a lot
because it is a kind of evidence
that on the day I took my policy,
I had this buffalo
and secondly, for precautions,
you should always fill the company's form yourself,
mostly the customer signs it and
asks the advisor to fill the form, it is better that
you fill the form yourself, if you have
any disease then give complete details about it, if you have it, if
you have ever smoked, if you
drink alcohol or
eat tobacco, it is
very important for you to give all those details, so if you have any
medical history then
give this People's Choice, but if there is no medical history,
if I have
told all my details correctly, when
I bought the policy I am healthy, and if I
fall ill after one and a half years, then it will be
valid, there is no need to
claim any comeback in the company by killing me in that policy,
you should also call as I
told this is a contract, on the day I
took the policy, the clear fact which is
important is that
I am fine today, if the work gets
corrected after today then this is not medical
too  The lines have been turned on. The
fax of only that day on which the bank policy was taken is
a good way to keep it important, which
Shailesh ji told that it can be a representative of the company,
so stay healthy, keep
yourself happy and show that you did
not have any disease, you bought it by drinking juice, this will
help you in future, all this
there, if you ask
how much time the company can take you to respond to any issue or give
its decision because
I have such people with you for months
because the competition is complete,
how much time it takes for them to
listen to me, no matter how much time they take to respond to me, look, the
turnaround time given
to the insurance company is 15 days, the
reply should have come within 15 days of the day I complained,
this is very picture,
not at all, subscribing is the way, if you do
not get a reply then
turn off the reminder number and call again, the
company will have to address this regulator that is
ours, IRDA, their Russian regulations are
very clear, thanks and for this company
If any finance company does not follow them, it has to
answer to the regulator. So, the
entire department of companies' benefit is with the
committee in which
they answer all these things. The
turnaround metric is reviewed every quarter. So, a
proper system should be carefully followed to handle the
disturbances. But what happens is that
our customers who are
not aware about this,
for them, Tehsildar Balwan Singh Tips, if a love affair
goes on, then the insurance limited was not there, that is
where the case arises. I think the companies
take action, we are less than before, we cannot
give it at all. If you are buying this policy for the
first time and if it is his
first time in life, then he has
not gone through six processes, the company takes
advantage of this and does as it pleases. No
one follows the turnaround time of 15 days.
You are saying that now you
should go to the consumer forum, how many
hearings can be held there, it remains pending for so long, so
for the buyers of insurance,
this path is very difficult. Absolutely, you
fully agree with him in this matter because it is a
complicated matter and it is
not that easy.  Button, as I
told you in the beginning,
this is a pen for the customer, and on it you will
write your emotions like I was robbed, ruined,
whatsapp Dr. Putt, if you do
n't write what you should have written, then for that you have to
first take the help of an expert who can
properly handle their issues,
we can see the end example of Vitamin E,
here the picture views were customer
guide, time I did
Prem forgetting, reject pickup,
documentation issues, okay, now if it happens then I will give
you a small example, when the
squad did not follow the standard practice protocol,
now there were no side effects, this time the
hospital also knows, after subscribing to this point
and getting
treatment, you have to
prove something to them, so you can prove it
and that is why relief becomes difficult,
but many avenues have been closed, in this
way
we will compare the features of term insurance competition with 2 tablespoons
so that you can understand them better
[Music]
Chittor